<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://billhertzing.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://billhertzing.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-04-06T11:31:55-06:00</updated><id>https://billhertzing.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Bill’s Blog</title><subtitle>Technical articles for my code repositories. Position papers on political issues. Cute pictures of the kids. I&apos;ve got it all!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Bill’s Blog!</title><link href="https://billhertzing.github.io/2021/04/06/Welcome-To-Bills-Blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Bill’s Blog!" /><published>2021-04-06T10:22:50-06:00</published><updated>2021-04-06T10:22:50-06:00</updated><id>https://billhertzing.github.io/2021/04/06/Welcome-To-Bills-Blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://billhertzing.github.io/2021/04/06/Welcome-To-Bills-Blog/">&lt;p&gt;This is my new Blog site, hosted by GitHub Pages.  I’ve never been satisfied with all the effort needed to setup a Blog on other hosting sites; GitHub Pages combined with the Jekyll static site generator seems like it will meet my needs with very simple administration overhead. We will see!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first post, appropriately, is on &lt;a href=&quot;TBD&quot;&gt;How I setup my Blog Hosting site Part 01&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog site will be organized into three sections&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Technical posts of interests to programmers and IT folks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blogs about political issues that I care about (Hey, a person’s gotta vent occasionally!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The goings-on of me, my family, and friends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be aware that the comments on these posts are handled by &lt;a href=&quot;https://utteranc.es/&quot;&gt;utterances&lt;/a&gt;) and comments are stored in this repository’s Issues, which means they are in GitHub which is owned by Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please bear with me as I learn the intricacies of Jekyll, static sites, and GitHub Pages!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This is my new Blog site, hosted by GitHub Pages. I’ve never been satisfied with all the effort needed to setup a Blog on other hosting sites; GitHub Pages combined with the Jekyll static site generator seems like it will meet my needs with very simple administration overhead. We will see!</summary></entry></feed>